<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nikhil Verma</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Nikhil Verma</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</managingEditor><webMaster>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</webMaster><copyright>&amp;copy; Nikhil Verma</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikhilweee.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speed up your remote workflow</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2022/speed-up-remote-workflow-slurm-nyu-hpc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2022/speed-up-remote-workflow-slurm-nyu-hpc/</guid><description>Although NYU already a dedicated website with all the documentation to get started with the HPC cluster, here&amp;rsquo;s a set of tricks that I use to ease up the workflow by a significant amount.
Table of Contents First things first 1. Passwordless SSH 2. Set up SSH aliases A few simple tricks 1. Login directly into compute nodes 2. Use local SSH keys Some SLURM aliases 1.</description></item><item><title>A Yucatecan Foodtrip</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2022/mexico-yucatecan-foodtrip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2022/mexico-yucatecan-foodtrip/</guid><description>Disclaimer: All recommendations made in the blog are solely based on personal experiences. There are no affiliate links, and I earn absolutely nothing should you choose to click on any of the links mentioned in this blog. 🧭 are Google Maps locations, and 🌎 are external websites.
Shavak and I had been planning to meet all winter. It was turning out to be difficult because he was working out of Vancouver and I was studying in New York, and neither of us had visas to the other country.</description></item><item><title>Intro to Style Transfer</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2020/intro-to-style-transfer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2020/intro-to-style-transfer/</guid><description>Image Style Transfer Using Convolutional Neural Networks This paper introduced neural style transfer. It uses a VGGNet pre-trained on the ImageNet dataset for the purpose. The key idea is to be able to separate content and style from the representations of the network. Once that is done, a new image is synthesized from white noise where two different kind of losses are minimized - a style loss between the style image and the hybrid image, and a content loss between the content image and the hybrid image.</description></item><item><title>Building your first RNN</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2018/first-rnn-pytorch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2018/first-rnn-pytorch/</guid><description>If you have some understanding of recurrent networks, want to get your hands dirty, but haven&amp;rsquo;t really tried to do that on your own, then you are certainly at the right place. This tutorial is a practical guide about getting started with recurrent networks using PyTorch. We&amp;rsquo;ll solve a simple cipher using PyTorch 0.4.0, which is the latest version at the time of this writing.
You are only expected to have some understanding of recurrent networks.</description></item><item><title>Triund</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/triund/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/triund/</guid><description>Prologue It was early December and for most BITSians this was the compre1 season. For me though, it is usually at this time of the year when weird ideas surface off. They did, this time too. Me and my friend Sameer were long planning to visit McLeodGanj in search of snow, and this was it. This was the long awaited break.
Dawn from Triund Hill
My previous experiences warned me from planning a trip long before its schedule.</description></item><item><title>Shadowsocks</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/shadowsocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/shadowsocks/</guid><description>Shadowsocks! Sounds like the new superhero after Deadpool. Well, in a way it is a superhero! It let&amp;rsquo;s you bypass censorship, even the GFW! 1 Okay, so what&amp;rsquo;s this fuss about? Before going further, I think it needs some introduction.
Shadowsocks is a SOCKS5 compatible proxy server/client suite which excels at being undetectable. It leaves no fingerprint even when you use deep packet inspection. 2
Whoa! Wait, What does that mean?</description></item><item><title>Persistent Mounts</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/persistent-mounts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/persistent-mounts/</guid><description>After installing your linux distro, though you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to access your Windows/NTFS partitions easily, things can get annoying sometimes with you having to mount the partition manually everytime. Here I describe how to get away with this mess by automatically mounting partitions on boot.
You could also do the same from Unity using the Disks utility, but here I describe the so called hard way. The way we do it is by editing the /etc/fstab file.</description></item><item><title>Shout IRC!</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/shout-irc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/shout-irc/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, there are high chances that you are under internet surveillance and your IT admin has blocked access to IRC. God! Why do they do this? IRC isn&amp;rsquo;t bad at all, you may argue. But unfortunately there&amp;rsquo;s no one to listen. Hush. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to find a way out, and here&amp;rsquo;s exactly how you can do it!
I&amp;rsquo;ll be using one of the many benefits of having your own server in the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Set up a Ghost blog</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/setup-ghost-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/setup-ghost-blog/</guid><description>Before you read This is not an in-depth tutorial for a total newbie. Something like that would make this a really long post. Though I&amp;rsquo;ve given one-liners explaining each command, It would be better if you had some experience working with the linux terminal and a basic understanding of how web content is served.
Things you&amp;rsquo;ll need Just the two of them will do
A Server : This is where your site contents will be stored.</description></item><item><title>Sticky Notes</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/sticky-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/sticky-notes/</guid><description>This page hosts little ideas, solutions to problems I&amp;rsquo;ve faced in the past or mistakes that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to repeat again - stored here as a reference in case they bother me again. Read on, maybe even you might find something relevant!
Table of Contents Some useful aliases Docker and DC++ Test outgoing ports Use Google Fonts offline Installing Node Installing OpenCV Raspberry Pi Configure Mutt with Gmail Remove Python Package with Dependencies Academic writing with Pandoc PuDB Custom Stringifier Interesting Jekyll Themes Some useful aliases Timesync!</description></item></channel></rss>