<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Nikhil Verma</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Nikhil Verma</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</managingEditor><webMaster>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</webMaster><copyright>&amp;copy; Nikhil Verma</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikhilweee.github.io/tags/linux/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Persistent Mounts</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/persistent-mounts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/persistent-mounts/</guid><description>After installing your linux distro, though you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to access your Windows/NTFS partitions easily, things can get annoying sometimes with you having to mount the partition manually everytime. Here I describe how to get away with this mess by automatically mounting partitions on boot.
You could also do the same from Unity using the Disks utility, but here I describe the so called hard way. The way we do it is by editing the /etc/fstab file.</description></item><item><title>Set up a Ghost blog</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/setup-ghost-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/setup-ghost-blog/</guid><description>Before you read This is not an in-depth tutorial for a total newbie. Something like that would make this a really long post. Though I&amp;rsquo;ve given one-liners explaining each command, It would be better if you had some experience working with the linux terminal and a basic understanding of how web content is served.
Things you&amp;rsquo;ll need Just the two of them will do
A Server : This is where your site contents will be stored.</description></item><item><title>Sticky Notes</title><link>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/sticky-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.github.io/blog/2016/sticky-notes/</guid><description>This page hosts little ideas, solutions to problems I&amp;rsquo;ve faced in the past or mistakes that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to repeat again - stored here as a reference in case they bother me again. Read on, maybe even you might find something relevant!
Table of Contents Some useful aliases Docker and DC++ Test outgoing ports Use Google Fonts offline Installing Node Installing OpenCV Raspberry Pi Configure Mutt with Gmail Remove Python Package with Dependencies Academic writing with Pandoc PuDB Custom Stringifier Interesting Jekyll Themes Some useful aliases Timesync!</description></item></channel></rss>