<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Long Posts on weeeblog</title><link>https://nikhilweee.me/blog/archives/long-posts/</link><description>Recent content in Long Posts on weeeblog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</managingEditor><webMaster>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</webMaster><copyright>&amp;copy; Nikhil Verma</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikhilweee.me/blog/archives/long-posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Yucatecan Foodtrip</title><link>https://nikhilweee.me/blog/2022/mexico-yucatecan-foodtrip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.me/blog/2022/mexico-yucatecan-foodtrip/</guid><description>Disclaimer: All recommendations made in the blog are solely based on personal experiences. There are no affiliate links, and most of them will anyway take you to Google Maps.
Shavak and I had been planning to meet all winter. It was turning out to be difficult because he was working out of Vancouver and I was studying in New York. Neither of us had visas to the other country.</description></item><item><title>Adversarial Attacks on RL Agents</title><link>https://nikhilweee.me/blog/2021/adversarial-attacks-deep-rl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.me/blog/2021/adversarial-attacks-deep-rl/</guid><description>This post a write up for the final project as part of NYU&amp;rsquo;s graduate course on Deep Reinforcement Learning. The project was the result of a collaboration with Advika Reddy.
Outline Abstract Background What are Adversarial Attacks? How are they different for RL Agents? Types of Adversarial Attacks White-box Attacks Black-box Attacks Motivation How do the adversarial policies exploit the victim?</description></item><item><title>Building your first RNN</title><link>https://nikhilweee.me/blog/2018/first-rnn-pytorch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nikhilweee@gmail.com (Nikhil Verma)</author><guid>https://nikhilweee.me/blog/2018/first-rnn-pytorch/</guid><description>If you have some understanding of recurrent networks, want to get your hands dirty, but haven&amp;rsquo;t really tried to do that on your own, then you are certainly at the right place. This tutorial is a practical guide about getting started with recurrent networks using PyTorch. We&amp;rsquo;ll solve a simple cipher using PyTorch 0.4.0, which is the latest version at the time of this writing.
Outline The Problem The Dataset Word Embeddings The Cipher The Dataset (Finally!</description></item></channel></rss>